

VALTER CALDEIRA

DATA SCIENTIST

> ABOUT ME

Start working as a full-stack java developer for 3 years. In 2017, I become a Data Scientist and create a team from scratch in Novabase GTE.

I have been working as Data Scientist and Team Leader. Responsible for creating and developing ML solutions, providing technical solutions that ensure application performance, lifecycle agility, maintainability and governance.

I'm always learning new technologies and love to challenging myself every day.

CONTACT

- +351 926 055 290
- valterjpcaldeira@gmail.com www.valterjpcaldeira.github.io
- ♥ Torres Vedras, Lisbon

INTERESTS





WORK EXPERIENCE

+ Lisbon, Tenthpin

2019 - Current

SENIOR DATA SCIENTIST

Several projects in healthcare: Article summarization and insights gathering for Research Company: Python (Keras, TensorFlow, Sklearn, Gensim, Nltk, etc.). Deployment of Invoice Classification for a drug company: Python (Pandas, Numpy, Sklearn, Tensorflow). Power BI dashboard and SAP ByDesign Reports Development

+ Lisbon, Novabase @GTE

2017 - 2019

DATA SCIENTIST

Several projects in government: Web Scraping project to gather insights about UK companies using NLP: Python (Selenium, MongoDB Atlas, Flask, Nginx, Sklearn, Gensim, Nltk.). Classify (CAE) activity code based on a description sentence (Portuguese Language): Python (Pandas, Numpy, Sklearn, Gensim). Using NLP algorithms to help ensure Quality control in Mozambique Census: Python (Pandas, Numpy, Levenshtein distance). POC for Transportation Company to count the number of persons inside a bus just using image: Python (OpenCV, Tensorflow, Angular, Websockets)

+ Lisbon, Novabase @Portal

2014 - 2017

JAVA FULL STACK DEVELOPER

Develop Information Systems using tools like: Spring, Liferay, SQL, Oracle DB, WebLogic, Jboss, Jenkins, Javascript.

SKILLS

PYTHON

NLP

AZURE

MACHINE LEARNING

POWER BI

DATA

EDUCATIONS / CERTIFICATES

+ Microsoft

2020

MICROSOFT CERTIFIED: AZURE FUNDAMENTALS

+ Genova, Università degli Studi di Genova

2018

INTERNATIONAL SUMMER SCHOOL ON DEEP LEARNING

Lisbon, Instituto Superior de engenharia de Lisboa

2010 - 2014

SOFTWARE AND COMPUTER ENGINEERING DEGREE